{
    "languages" : [
        {
            "language" : "css",
            "questions" : [
                {
                    "numb" : 1,
                    "question" : "Which of the following property specifies whether an element is an accelerator indicator or not.",
                    "answer" : "accelerator",
                    "options" : [
                        "move",
                        "@keyframes",
                        "accelerator",
                        "none of the mentioned"
                    ]
                },
                {
                    "numb" : 2,
                    "question" : "Which of the following property is used to define the animations that should be run?",
                    "answer" : "animation-name",
                    "options" : [
                        "animation-delay",
                        "animation-iteration-count",
                        "animation-duration",
                        "animation-name"
                    ]
                },
                {
                    "numb" : 3,
                    "question" : "Which of the following property is used to define the number of times an animation should play?",
                    "answer" : "animation-iteration-count",
                    "options" : [
                        "animation-direction",
                        "animation-iteration-count",
                        "animation",
                        "animation-timing-function"
                    ]
                },
                {
                    "numb" : 4,
                    "question" : "YWhich of the following property is used to indicate whether the backside of an element is visible if the element is rotated to display the back?",
                    "answer" : "backface-visibility",
                    "options" : [
                        "background-clip",
                        "backface-visibility",
                        "behavior",
                        "background-origin"
                    ]
                },
                {
                    "numb" : 5,
                    "question" : "Which of the following property defines a relationship between bound elements(s) and some code or content?",
                    "answer" : "binding",
                    "options" : [
                        "behavior",
                        "anim",
                        "binding",
                        "none of the mentioneds"
                    ]
                }
            ]
        },
        {
            "language" : "python",
            "questions" : [
                {
                    "numb" : 1,
                    "question" : "Who developed Python Programming Language?",
                    "answer" : "Guido van Rossum",
                    "options" : [
                        "Wick van Rossum",
                        "Rasmus Lerdorf",
                        "Guido van Rossum",
                        "Niene Stom"
                    ]
                },
                {
                    "numb" : 2,
                    "question" : "Which type of Programming does Python support?",
                    "answer" : "all of the mentioned",
                    "options" : [
                        "object-oriented programming",
                        "structured programming",
                        "functional programming",
                        "all of the mentioned"
                    ]
                },
                {
                    "numb" : 3,
                    "question" : "Is Python case sensitive when dealing with identifiers?",
                    "answer" : "no",
                    "options" : [
                        "no",
                        "yes",
                        "machine dependent",
                        "none of the mentioned"
                    ]
                },
                {
                    "numb" : 4,
                    "question" : "Which of the following is the correct extension of the Python file?",
                    "answer" : "backface-visibility",
                    "options" : [
                        ".python",
                        ".pl",
                        ".py",
                        ".p"
                    ]
                },
                {
                    "numb" : 5,
                    "question" : "Is Python code compiled or interpreted?",
                    "answer" : "Python code is neither compiled nor interpreted",
                    "options" : [
                        "Python code is both compiled and interpreted",
                        "Python code is neither compiled nor interpreted",
                        "Python code is only compiled",
                        "Python code is only interpreted"
                    ]
                }
            ]  
        },
        {
            "language" : "nodejs",
            "questions" : [
                {
                    "numb" : 1,
                    "question" : "Which of the following is true about RESTful web services?",
                    "answer" : "Both of the above",
                    "options" : [
                        "Webservices based on REST Architecture are known as RESTful web services",
                        " Webservices uses HTTP methods to implement the concept of REST architecture",
                        "Both of the above",
                        "none of the mentioned"
                    ]
                },
                {
                    "numb" : 2,
                    "question" : "The Node.js modules can be exposed using",
                    "answer" : "module.exports",
                    "options" : [
                        "module.expose",
                        "module",
                        "module.exports",
                        "All of the above"
                    ]
                },
                {
                    "numb" : 3,
                    "question" : "In Nodejs how node based web servers differ from traditional web servers?",
                    "answer" : "Node based server uses a single threaded model and can serve much larger number of requests compared to any traditional server like Apache HTTP Server.",
                    "options" : [
                        "Node based server uses a single threaded model and can serve much larger number of requests compared to any traditional server like Apache HTTP Server.",
                        "Node based server process request much faster than traditional server.",
                        "There is no much difference between the two.",
                        "All of the above"
                    ]
                },
                {
                    "numb" : 4,
                    "question" : "Which statement executes the code of sample.js file?",
                    "answer" : "node sample.js",
                    "options" : [
                        "nodejs sample.js",
                        "node sample.js",
                        "sample.js",
                        "None of the above"
                    ]
                },
                {
                    "numb" : 5,
                    "question" : "What are the key features of Node.js?",
                    "answer" : "All of the above",
                    "options" : [
                        "Real time Data intensive",
                        "Highly scalable servers for Web Applications",
                        " Builds fast and scalable network Applications",
                        "All of the above"
                    ]
                },
                {
                    "numb" : 6,
                    "question" : "Child processes always have three streams child.stdin, child.stdout, and child.stderr which may be shared with the stdio streams of the parent process.",
                    "answer" : "false",
                    "options" : [
                        "false",
                        "true",
                        "All the above",
                        "None"
                    ]
                }                
            ]
        },
        {
            "language" : "java",
            "questions" : [
                {
                    "numb" : 1,
                    "question" : "Which of these class have only one field ‘TYPE’?",
                    "answer" : "Void",
                    "options" : [
                        "Void",
                        "Process",
                        "System",
                        "Runtime"
                    ]
                },
                {
                    "numb" : 2,
                    "question" : "Which of the following method of Process class can terminate a process?",
                    "answer" : "void destroy()",
                    "options" : [
                        "void kill()",
                        "void destroy()",
                        "void terminate()",
                        "void exit()"
                    ]
                },
                {
                    "numb" : 3,
                    "question" : "Standard output variable ‘out’ is defined in which class?",
                    "answer" : "System",
                    "options" : [
                        "Void",
                        "Process",
                        "Runtime",
                        "System"
                    ]
                },
                {
                    "numb" : 4,
                    "question" : "Which of the following is method of System class is used to find how long a program takes to execute?",
                    "answer" : "currentTimeMillis()",
                    "options" : [
                        "currenttime()",
                        "currentTime()",
                        "currentTimeMillis()",
                        "currenttimeMillis()"
                    ]
                },
                {
                    "numb" : 5,
                    "question" : "Which of this method of class String is used to extract a substring from a String object?",
                    "answer" : " substring()",
                    "options" : [
                        " substring()",
                        "Substring()",
                        "SubString()",
                        "All of the above"
                    ]
                },
                {
                    "numb" : 6,
                    "question" : "Which of the following statement is correct?",
                    "answer" : "replace() method replaces all occurrences of one character in invoking string with another character",
                    "options" : [
                        "replace() method replaces all occurrences of one character in invoking string with another character",
                        "replace() method replaces only first occurrences of a character in invoking string with another character",
                        "replace() method replaces all the characters in invoking string with another character",
                        "replace() method replaces last occurrence of a character in invoking string with another character"
                    ]
                }                
            ]
        },
        {
            "language" : "js",
            "questions" : [
                {
                    "numb" : 1,
                    "question" : "Which of the following is true?",
                    "answer" : "If onKeyDown returns false, the key-press event is cancelled.",
                    "options" : [
                        "If onKeyDown returns false, the key-press event is cancelled.",
                        "If onKeyPress returns false, the key-down event is cancelled.",
                        "If onKeyDown returns false, the key-up event is cancelled.",
                        "If onKeyDown returns false, the key-up event is cancelled."
                    ]
                },
                {
                    "numb" : 2,
                    "question" : "Which best explains getSelection()?",
                    "answer" : "Returns the value of cursor-selected text",
                    "options" : [
                        "Returns the VALUE of a selected OPTION.",
                        "Returns document.URL of the window in focus.",
                        "Returns the value of cursor-selected text",
                        "Returns the VALUE of a checked radio input."
                    ]
                },
                {
                    "numb" : 3,
                    "question" : "Choose the client-side JavaScript object:",
                    "answer" : "FileUpLoad",
                    "options" : [
                        "Database",
                        "Cursor",
                        "Client",
                        "FileUpLoad"
                    ]
                },
                {
                    "numb" : 4,
                    "question" : "Javascript is a ________ typed language.",
                    "answer" : "loosly",
                    "options" : [
                        "tightly",
                        "loosly"
                    ]
                },
                {
                    "numb" : 5,
                    "question" : "Javascript is a ________ typed language.",
                    "answer" : " blur()",
                    "options" : [
                        "blur()",
                        "focus()",
                        "None"
                    ]
                },
                {
                    "numb" : 6,
                    "question" : "What property would you use to redirect a visitor to another page?",
                    "answer" : "window.location.href",
                    "options" : [
                        "document.URL",
                        "window.location.href",
                        ".document.location.href",
                        "link.href"
                    ]
                }                
            ]
        },
        {
            "language" : "html5",
            "questions" : [
                {
                    "numb" : 1,
                    "question" : " __________Function displays the Latitude and Longitude in geoLocation in HTML5",
                    "answer" : "showPosition()",
                    "options" : [
                        "showLocation()",
                        "showPosition()",
                        "both a and b",
                        "showStatus()"
                    ]
                },
                {
                    "numb" : 2,
                    "question" : "Which of the following browser supports HTML5 in its latest version?",
                    "answer" : "Both of them",
                    "options" : [
                        "Apple Safari",
                        "Google Chrome",
                        "Both of them",
                        "None of the above"
                    ]
                },
                {
                    "numb" : 3,
                    "question" : "Which of the following tag represents a piece of content that is only slightly related to the rest of the page in HTML5?",
                    "answer" : "aside",
                    "options" : [
                        "section",
                        "article",
                        "aside",
                        "header"
                    ]
                },
                {
                    "numb" : 4,
                    "question" : "Which of the following input control accepts only numerical value in Web Form 2.0?",
                    "answer" : "number",
                    "options" : [
                        "week",
                        "time",
                        "number",
                        "range"
                    ]
                },
                {
                    "numb" : 5,
                    "question" : "Which of the following tag provides a hint to the user of what can be entered in the field in HTML5?",
                    "answer" : " placeholder()",
                    "options" : [
                        "output",
                        "placeholder",
                        "autofocus",
                        "required"
                    ]
                },
                {
                    "numb" : 6,
                    "question" : "Which of the following is correct about geolocation api in HTML5?",
                    "answer" : "All of the above",
                    "options" : [
                        "HTML5 Geolocation API lets you share your location with your favorite web sites.",
                        " A Javascript can capture your latitude and longitude and can be sent to backend web server and do fancy location-aware things like finding local businesses or showing your location on a map.",
                        "Today most of the browsers and mobile devices support Geolocation API.",
                        "All of the above"
                    ]
                }                
            ]  
        }
    ]
}
